This is my kitchen table and also my
filing system.
Over much of the past three decades,
I've been an investor the highest
quality of mankind I've often thought
was private equity.
And then I started interviewing.
Oh, I watch your interviews cause I know
how to do something.
I've learned in doing my interviews how
leaders make it to the top.
I asked him how much he wanted.
He said to 50.
I said, Fine.
I didn't negotiate with him.
I didn't know due diligence.
I have something I'd like to sell and
how they stay there.
You don't feel inadequate now because
being only the second wealthiest man in
the world, Is that right?
One of the most successful IPO's in 2025
was the IPO of circle, a regulated
stablecoin network.
The company was the brainchild of Jeremy
Allaire.
I recently had a chance to sit down with
Jeremy Lehr to talk about what a
regulated stablecoin network is and why
it's the future of banking.
The company is now has a market
capitalisation today of about March
20 something around their $20 billion.
That's pretty good.
And you own about 10% of the company
close to that.
Yeah.
So you're a happy guy.
I've been building the company for 12
and a half years.
It's been a very long journey to build
it and it and a company that very few
people believed could achieve what it
has.
So I feel great about what we've been
able to build.
What I would say, though, and it relates
to the IPO as well, is
what's motivating to me is that, you
know, we're actually an early stage
company.
This is super early in terms of what we
envision being possible and what we can
build.
And so while the numbers or this or that
are are interesting or compelling for
different reasons, what's exciting to me
is that, you know, by becoming a
publicly held institution, the general
public can participate in how we build
this company over the long run.
And, you know, the law that even made
what we do kind of enshrined in federal
law and part of the global financial
system just passed, and it's not even in
effect.
So we're in the early days of this.
And so that's really motivating to me is
what we can accomplish still.
When what year did you start the
company?
In 2013.
And who gave you your initial capital?
So our original investors were general
Catalyst.
Jim Breyer and Xcel were the kind of
founding and they made on their money.
They did well.
Well,
wow.
Okay.
And they get the circle off the ground.
It took how much capital?
10 million.
15?
20.
Yeah.
I mean, in the first couple of years, we
raised around, you know, $25 million and
then people know what a stablecoin was
in those days.
Well, there was no such thing as a
stablecoin then.
But when we started the company, what we
explained was this new technology,
cryptocurrency blockchains, was was
going to make it possible to build a way
to put dollars on the Internet in the
same way that we have protocols for how
information moves around, like the Web
protocols or email protocols or voice
protocols and all these things.
There are going to be these new
protocols for money on the Internet that
will allow very safe forms of dollars to
be operated that way.
And that was the idea.
And you couldn't do it in 2013.
What is a stablecoin and what does
Circle actually do with Stablecoins?
We now have a law that defines what a
stablecoin is in the United States, so
I'll use that definition.
Okay.
A payment Stablecoin is a digital
currency that is issued on a on the
internet, on a blockchain that is backed
completely one for one by high quality,
safe liquid assets, so the US
government, Treasury bills and cash.
And by issuing it on these networks, it
allows these digital dollars to be used
on the Internet, just like we can use
any form of data and information as
well.
So it is a form of digital currency
dollars that is fully backed and held,
and it's called a stablecoin because of
course historically cryptocurrencies
were not stable and volatile and that's
really where the name came from.
And circle, we operate an Internet
platform across a whole range of
technologies, but the core franchise is
we run the largest regulated stablecoin
network in the world for handling
stablecoins and storing and moving them
all around the internet.
Well, why do I need a stablecoin?
I've been using banks for years.
What's wrong with my banks?
And if I want to send money to to
Istanbul, I can just tell the bank and
wire the money.
What's wrong with that system?
Well, if you talk to anyone who's trying
to move money to Istanbul, it actually
turns out it's very time consuming, very
slow.
There's a lot of barriers.
There's tends to be excessive fees.
Sometimes it gets lost.
And in fact, Turkey is a great example
because in Turkey, there's extraordinary
demand for Usdc in Stablecoins right
now, because in a place like Turkey,
people want dollars, they don't want
lira, they want digital dollars that
they can just use from their mobile
phones, that they can just like you can
make a a peer to peer phone call with
someone.
It doesn't cost you anything.
People and businesses have figured out
in Turkey, just as one example, that
they can transact with each other
directly without an intermediary
instantly with virtually no cost.
And so it's it's actually becoming a
substitute for banking.
And in fact, the nice thing about
Stablecoins, especially well-regulated,
well-run stablecoins, is they're very
safe because they don't actually lend
the money or take risk with the money.
They just are holding it in these ultra
safe instruments.
So holders of these are saying, Wow,
this is a super safe.
Digital dollar that I can use, just like
I can use WhatsApp or use like the
internet as a whole.
It's such a great idea.
How come everybody isn't doing it?
How come you don't have 1000
competitors?
Well, historically, there actually have
been hundreds of companies that have
launched Stablecoins and hundreds of
these have launched and are, you know,
as one of my colleagues says, stable in
name only.
And it's only very recently, just the
past couple of years that there have
been regulations on this.
We've advocated for regulations from day
one, but the regulations have come into
effect and in particular in the United
States, but in Japan and Hong Kong and
Europe and all over the world, there's
regulations on this.
But once you once you have that
regulatory clarity, then there's sort of
an open, free competitive market.
And so there are a lot more companies
getting involved in this now.
And so we're going to have we already
have more competition.
There's going to be a lot more.
Ten years from today, will banks be
around to wire money anywhere or will
your system take over what banks do
today over a ten year period?
Software utilities that are built
entirely on an open Internet
infrastructure on the public Internet
with software are going to exist and
likely be as large are larger than the
biggest banks in the world.
But those bank many of these banks will
also figure out, Hey, I can build on
this technology too.
Just like media companies have made that
move or communications companies have
gotten involved in the Internet as well.
You went public last year.
Yes, right.
And you pay your underwriters price it
at $31 a share.
That's right.
And at the end of the day, what was the
stock price?
It was around $80.
And then you think maybe they had
underpriced it and they left a lot of
money on the table.
When you're doing an IPO, as you know,
you're trying to do a couple of things.
You're trying to get as broad of a base
of investors involved as you can,
especially major investors.
We did that.
We had a deal that we actually started
with a price.
We upsized the price multiple times and
then we price yet again.
Above that, we increased the size of the
deal significantly.
So we grew the capacity of it all the
way throughout that.
So we had all of these things that were
happening and then the deal was 25 times
oversubscribed on roughly a billion, so
$25 billion of demand.
And and so that we knew we had a great
investor base, but it was really hard to
know, you know, what that was going to
do in the market.
There hadn't been a lot of IPOs.
In fact, we were like the first major
IPO.
The IPO that had come hadn't been the
spectacular thing.
So it was hard to know.
There aren't many companies like this.
And so I think, you know, there ended up
being a lot of individuals and family
offices and others that wanted to own
stock.
And obviously that that performed very
well.
Now, in the technology world, everybody
United States always says we have to
worry about the Chinese.
The Chinese are going to take our
technology and improve it or do
something different.
Is there a Chinese company that's
equivalent to circle?
There's not.
And in fact, what's interesting about
this space is for those that are
familiar with the kind of the early DNA
of the Internet, the the Internet has,
you know, you know, kind of open,
accessible, permissionless,
decentralized, open source.
Like these are like the fabric of what's
given the Internet so much of its of its
strength.
And in fact, those ideas are inherently
come out of, I would call the liberal
enlightenment, they're liberal
enlightenment ideals, and they're
expressed in technology and software and
protocols.
And I think that's that's intrinsic in
blockchains as well.
Those ideals are expressed there.
And so if you're a society that is
fundamentally built around
centralization, total control, you know,
etc., and where, you know, privacy or
freedom are not the highest ideals, you
don't end up building things like this.
But let's go back and talk about your
background for a moment.
Where were you born?
I was born in Philadelphia in 1971,
giving my age.
Okay.
And then you and your family moved from
there?
We did.
We moved when I was around 11 years old
to a small town in Minnesota.
We're now in Minnesota, southeastern
Minnesota.
So you moved to Minnesota?
Yeah.
And you have a brother?
My brother?
Yes, I'm brother.
Okay.
And he's actually here.
Where is he?
Oh, there he is.
Okay.
Well, I see he's got the same hairline
you have, right?
Okay.
All right.
So.
All right, you move to Minnesota.
And then.
Were you a good student in school?
Yeah, I think so.
I was more interested in in debate and
model.
Model United Nations.
I So you did well in high school, I
assume.
And then where did you go to college?
I went to McAllister College in the Twin
Cities.
Walter Mondale School.
Walter Mondale.
Kofi Annan.
Yeah.
Walter Mondale.
And you hear the more famous and those
guys now.
Okay.
All right.
So after you graduated, what did you do?
So when I graduated, it was 1993, and I
thought I would get a job in policy work
because I did political science and
philosophy and there wasn't really
easily accessible policy work.
But while I was in college, I had become
really obsessed with the Internet in
pre-commercial Internet days, starting
in like 1990.
Got really excited about it.
And shortly after graduating college, I
just said, You know what?
Like, this is going to be the future.
And I'm I'm an Internet consultant.
So I decided I'm an Internet consultant.
What are your parents say?
They said I was.
My dad was very concerned.
I mean, he was very concerned and
Internet consultant in 1990.
And there wasn't much of Internet,
wasn't there?
I mean, there was gopher.
Okay.
All right.
So you as a consult, did you have any
clients?
I did.
So I started I started working with I
got connected into
marketing agencies, some like PC firms,
others basically who wanted to and this
was in 1993, the very first Web browser,
the very first graphical web browser
came out in 1993, and I got really
excited that, wow, this is going to
reshape how communications and media and
software works.
And so I just said everyone needs to
build on the web.
And so I started creating web web stuff,
video compliance that I did.
They would pay me by the hour on the
hour.
Yes.
Okay.
And did you know Steve Case then or I,
of course, knew Steve Case, but I didn't
know personally until much later when he
invested in my next company.
Really?
Okay.
So then you started a company, Another
company after the Internet consulting
company?
Yes.
And what was that cleverly named?
Well, so that was actually a name chosen
by my brother called Aware Corporate
America.
Yes.
Was it hard to get that name?
I think we still have the domain because
we bought it from Adobe who ended up
owning the company and its assets.
Right.
So you started a layer corporation or
company.
What did it do?
So Altair built some of the very first
software products to to create
interactive applications on the web.
So in 1994, 1995, the idea was, hey,
instead of building software that gets
put on a personal computer, you could
build software that is distributed
through a web browser.
And the first product called called
Fusion
created a very simple way for someone
who was not that technical to create a
software program.
And you ran on the Web and was were you
still living in Minnesota?
Yeah, in in the Twin Cities.
Anybody tell you that probably wasn't
the center of the Internet world at the
time?
Well, our our venture capital investors,
in fact, said you got to move.
So did you actually move at some point?
We did.
And as the story goes,
my brother and other colleagues were
signing a lease in Silicon Valley in
Menlo Park to move the company there
because that was where the Internet was
going to happen.
But the venture capital firm, which was
a startup VC at the time, Polaris
Venture Partners,
said, you know, all their all their kind
of contacts were out on the East Coast
and in the Boston area.
And so we actually said, well, you know
what, We'll go to Boston.
We had East Coast Heritage, as you know,
some of the founders, my brother and I,
and we thought, you know, building a
company, a tech software company, there
will sort of be easier than being
crowded out.
Okay.
So you moved to Boston?
Yes.
How big that the company become.
So that company grew to over a hundred
million and revenue went public in early
1999.
So when the great Internet bubble burst
occurred in 98, 99, 2000, what happened
to your company?
We had a great franchise, meaning we had
an incredibly loyal customer base.
And over time, literally millions of
developers used our software to build
web.
Sites and applications.
And we we decided to merge with another
Internet software company called
Macromedia that that made some of the
most popular tools for building the web
and building content on the web.
We merged the companies together, two
public companies in.
And what was it then called a Layer of
Macromedia that was just Macromedia.
Effectively, they actually gave up the
eLearning.
Yes.
Okay.
And how long did you stay at Macromedia
for?
About two years.
Really?
Okay.
And then when you left, what did you do
next?
Well, so while I was at Macromedia, I
was the chief technology officer.
And we released in into the market a
technology called Flash, you know.
Many of you probably remember Flash
player.
You couldn't use the Internet values
using flash player.
Thank you.
All right.
We actually in 2002, put the best video
technology that the Internet had ever
seen into flash.
And within a year, every computer in the
world, 98% of computers in the world
could playback video more smoothly.
And I got very excited about this.
And I got excited that, you know,
there's going to be a video publishing
revolution and that every person, every
business, every media company could be
transformed and essentially television
would move to the Internet.
And so this was in 2002 and 2003.
I left and then went as entrepreneur in
residence at General Catalyst, which was
the venture capital firm, venture
capital firm in Cambridge at the time.
And and they were a startup VC really
then and, and incubated this idea and
then and then founded it officially in
2004.
That company was Brightcove.
Brightcove grew over the next half a
decade.
We had a successful IPO in 2012 and the
company powered many of the television
and media streaming infrastructures for
a lot of media companies, major brands
and others.
So we took two companies public.
That's a lot.
And so is Brightcove now been bought by
somebody else or it has been.
It's a private equity firm.
Took it private.
Okay.
So after that company was bought or
sold, I took I took breakup public in
2000, in early 2012, and I got immersed
in this whole technology of crypto later
in 2012.
And then I, I stepped down as CEO in, in
the beginning of 2013.
And then I started Circle.
When I started the company, I told the
early employees and the early board
members and investors, this is like a 10
to 20 year thing to accomplish what we
think we can accomplish.
And now when I look at where we are,
where I look at, where I see the
progression of this technology and the
future impact, and I'm like, there's
another 10 to 20 years here.
So I'm trying to build a very long
lasting institution.
And I think it can be fundamental to
changing not just the financial system,
but the way the broader economic system
works.
Over the next ten years.
They're going to be very significant
Internet financial platform companies
that are major utilities for the way the
financial and economic system work.
And we hope to be one of those.
We're working on that.
All right.
So let me ask you.
I want to know about the future, because
the future is where I want to invest.
So
is artificial intelligence going to be
good for society and are people going to
lose their jobs?
Are people going to get more jobs
because of artificial intelligence?
It's very likely, in my view, that
artificial intelligence is going to
pretty dramatically disrupt the labor
market as we know it today.
And it's going to you know, I think
there's huge numbers of of human labor
jobs that will be replaced by not
private equity, though.
Never, never, never, never.
I do I do think that there's going to be
a huge a huge amount of displacement
from from AI.
And
at the same time and this is what you
know, what I tell all my employees, we
have a very aggressive AI adoption
posture in our company.
And what I've told, you know, every
employee in the company is
you want to become really good at using
these tools.
It's sort of like when personal
computers came out, you could have
chosen to learn how to use a spreadsheet
or word processor or when the Internet
came out, you could have chosen to like
decide to figure out all this stuff.
Like these are choices that people make
and in their careers they have to make
these choices.
Now, not everyone has that opportunity.
So I'm obviously it's different because
I'm sort of shepherding this, but my
view is that the capabilities that
humans will have and do have already
through the application of AI are
extraordinary and will continue to be
extraordinary.
And so human capital and I, i labor are
going to are going to work closely
together.
And and it's that orchestration of that
that is going to be some of the highest
value labor that's out there.
What about quantum computing?
Is that the next wave of the future?
Is that going to happen?
All of the fundamental infrastructure
that we run on is built on cryptography.
Crypto is cryptography, and it's applied
cryptography, and it uses cryptography
for security.
It uses cryptography for kind of kind of
systems to prove data and other things.
And so cryptography and the resilience
of cryptography is a really critical
thing.
And so when people think about quantum,
one of the first things they think about
is breaking cryptography.
And if you can break cryptography, then
all bets are off, right?
You can just pour into an energy grid or
you could take over banks, you could do
whatever.
And so
as we build our systems, we are studying
what is, you know, what is quantum
cryptography going to look like?
What is quantum resistant cryptography,
And we're actively working on
engineering and working in communities
that are working on quantum resistant
tech.
Now, when when people sort of say, well,
what's the what's the time horizon on
that?
You hear a lot of different estimates on
that.
But I think we feel compelled that in
2026 and 2027, we need to have
infrastructure that is quantum ready, if
you will, from a security perspective.
So I don't know what that means in terms
of
when it's when it's available.
Obviously, the implications are
extraordinary in terms of this scale of
computing and what it could be applied
in.
And I think obviously when you think
about quantum in coordination with other
technology things that we have going on,
if you want to know technology well.
So this example I'm using what I call
last adopter.
I'm still trying to use a BlackBerry,
but nobody else wants to use them.
So what do you use for technology?
You have how many computers do you have?
Do you have iPads, how many smartphones
you use, and how often do you spend your
how many hours a day do you spend
looking at your screens?
I use an iPhone.
I use tablets, I use laptops.
And I and I have a variety of those and
some that I will use strictly for
personal reasons and others for work.
And you should be worried about people
hacking you.
So.
Absolutely.
So you have a pretty good anti hacking
system.
We have a lot of of cyber security.
What do you want most people to leave
here tonight knowing about circle?
I would say a couple of things.
I think the first is that we're still in
the very early days of this technology.
And while the aggregate numbers sound
really big, there's, you know, trillions
of dollars of transactions and all this
stuff.
We're really, really in the early days.
And if you think about what circle's
trying to do, we are really we're not
just our Stablecoin network.
We are we're building a whole set of
infrastructure, operating system,
infrastructure platforms for developers,
these monetary systems and utilities to
use all of this.
And our view is that over the next ten
years, they're going to be just like
we've had Internet platform companies
that came up for, say, communications or
for digital media or for selling
products and services or for.
Mobile handsets and other things.
We believe that over the next ten years
they're are going to be very significant
Internet financial platform companies
that are major utilities for the way the
financial and economic system work.
And we hope to be one of those we're
working on that to.